- I'm Liz, the CEO and founder of PO' UP!
Card Game,
which are party games celebrating black experiences
from college to the workplace.
I've been an Amazon seller for a couple of years now,
and here are my tips for participating
in the Amazon Vine program.
How does the Vine program work?
So you as a seller will have the opportunity
to dedicate a number of your products,
whether that's five, 10, or up to 30,
to donate to reviewers who will spend their time interacting
with your product and providing you with a certified review.
Why is this important?
Because if you're new to Amazon, it may be difficult
getting those first few customers organically
if you don't have any reviews on your page.
And we all know that reviews are a super important element
of Amazon and reviews also influence
whether a customer is going to be interested
in purchasing your product.
So to opt into the Amazon Vine program,
you'll go to Seller Central.
You'll identify the dropdown for the Vine program.
You will select the number of products
that you're interested in donating
to reviewers for the program.
And then reviewers will have the opportunity
to select whether they're interested in your product
or not.
Once they select that they're interested,
the product will be shipped to them,
and then they will have the opportunity
to leave an honest review of your product.
I highly recommend the Amazon Vine program for sellers
who are new to Amazon and looking for ways
to garner organic and honest reviews of their product.
Just remember that you have no control
over what those reviews will entail.
And if you have a product that has a large target audience
or demographic, the Vine program may be perfect for you.